{
  "title": "Computer_Network - Data_Link_Layer — Slot 2 (15 Questions)",
  "duration": 42,
  "sections": [
    {
      "name": "Data_Link_Layer — Slot 2",
      "questions": [
        {
          "id": 1,
          "question": "<p>An Ethernet frame that is  less than the IEEE 802.3 minimum length of 64 octets is called <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2017)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>Short frame</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>Small frame</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Mini frame</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>Runt frame</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>Runt frame</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/128662/isro2017-33\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 2,
          "question": "<p>Which media access control protocol is used by IEEE 802.11 wireless LAN? <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2017)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>CDMA</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>CSMA/CA</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>ALOHA</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>None of the above</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>CSMA/CA</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/128661/isro2017-32\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 3,
          "question": "<p>Consider two hosts X and Y, connected by a single direct link of rate \\(10^{6}\\) bits/sec . The\ndistance between the two hosts is 10,000 km and the propagation speed along the link is\n2x\\(10^{8}\\) m/sec . Host X sends a file of 50,000 bytes as one large message to host Y\ncontinuously. Let the transmission and propagation delays be p milliseconds and q\nmilliseconds, respectively . Then the values of p and q are <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2017 SET-2)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>p = 50 and q = 100</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>p = 50 and q = 400</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>p = 100 and q = 50</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>p = 400 and q = 50</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>p = 400 and q = 50</p>",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0.67,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/118537/gate2017-2-35#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 4,
          "question": "<p>Consider a binary code that consists of only four valid code words as given below:<br>\n00000,01011,10101,11110<br>\nLet the minimum Hamming distance of the code be p and the maximum number of erroneous\nbits that can be corrected by the code be q. Then the values of p and q are <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2017 SET-2)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>p = 3 and q = 1</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>p = 3 and q = 2</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>p = 4 and q = 2</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>p = 4 and q = 1</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>p = 3 and q = 1</p>",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0.67,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/118376/gate2017-2-34#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 5,
          "question": "<p>The values of parameters for the Stop-and-Wait ARQ protocol are as given below:<br><br>\nBit rate of the transmission channel = 1Mbps <br>\nPropagation delay from sender to receiver = 0.75 ms <br>\nTime to process a frame = 0.25ms <br>\nNumber of bytes in the information frame =1980 <br>\nNumber of bytes in the acknowledge frame = 20          <br>                               Number of overhead bytes in the information frame = 20 <br><br>\nAssume that there are no transmission errors. Then the transmission efficiency ( expressed in\npercentage) of the Stop-and - Wait ARQ protocol for the above parameters is _________(\ncorrect to 2 decimal places) <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2017 SET-1)</strong></p>",
          "type": "numeric",
          "options": [],
          "correct_answer": "86.5",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/118328/gate2017-1-45#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 6,
          "question": "<p>A computer network uses polynomials over GF(2) for error checking with 8 bits as\ninformation bits and uses \\(x^{3}+x+1\\) as the generator polynomial to generate the check bits. In\nthis network, the message 01011011 is transmitted as <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2017 SET-1)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>01011011010</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>01011011011</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>01011011101</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>01011011100</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>01011011101</p>",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0.67,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/118313/gate2017-1-32#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 7,
          "question": "<p>Frames of 1000 bits are sent over a \\(10^6\\) bps duplex link between two hosts. The propagation time is 25 ms. Frames are to be transmitted into this link to maximally pack them in transit (within the link).<br>What is the minimum number of bits (I) that will be required to represent the sequence numbers distinctly? Assume that no time gap needs to be given between transmission of two frames. <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2016)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>I=2</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>I=3</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>I=4</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>I=5</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>I=5</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/1340/gate2009-57-isro2016-75\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 8,
          "question": "<p>The message 11001001 is to be transmitted using the CRC polynomial \\(x^3 +1\\) to protect it from errors. The message that should be transmitted is: <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2016)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>\\(11001001000\\)</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>\\(11001001011\\)</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>\\(11001010\\)</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>\\(110010010011\\)</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>\\(11001001011\\)</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/1266/gate2007-68-isro2016-73\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 9,
          "question": "<p>In a token ring network the transmission speed is \\(10^7\\) bps and the propagation speed is 200 meters/\\(\\mu s\\). The 1-bit delay in this network is equivalent to: <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2016)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>500 meters of cable.</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>200 meters of cable.</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>20 meters of cable.</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>50 meters of cable.</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>20 meters of cable.</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/1264/gate2007-66-isro2016-71\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 10,
          "question": "<p>In Ethernet CSMA/CD, the special bit sequence transmitted by media access management to handle collision is called <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2016)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>Preamble</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>Postamble</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Jam</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>None of these</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>Jam</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/55519/isro2016-69\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 11,
          "question": "<p>Consider a \\(128 \\times 10^{3}\\) bits/second satellite communication link with one way propagation delay of 150 milliseconds. Selective retransmission(repeat) protocol is used on this link to send data with a frame size of 1 kilobyte. Neglect the transmission time of acknowledgement. The minimum number of bits required for the sequence number field to achieve 100% utilization is ________. <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2016 SET-2)</strong></p>",
          "type": "numeric",
          "options": [],
          "correct_answer": "4",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/39577/gate2016-2-55#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 12,
          "question": "<p>For the IEEE802.11 MAC protocol for wireless communication,which of the following\nstatements is/are TRUE?<br>\nI. At least three non-overlapping channels are available for transmissions.<br>\nII. The RTS-CTS mechan is misused for collision detection.<br>\nIII. Unicast frames are ACKed. <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2016 SET-2)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>All I,II,andIII</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>I andIIIonly</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>II andIIIonly</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>II only</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>I andIIIonly</p>",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0.67,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/39593/gate2016-2-54#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 13,
          "question": "<p>A network has a data transmission bandwidth of \\(20 \\times 10^{6}\\) bits per second. It uses CSMA/CD in the MAClayer. The maximum signal propagation time from one node to another node is 40 microseconds. The minimum size of a frame in the network is  ______ bytes. <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2016 SET-2)</strong></p>",
          "type": "numeric",
          "options": [],
          "correct_answer": "200",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/39589/gate2016-2-53#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 14,
          "question": "<p>In an Ethernet local area network,which one of the following statements is TRUE? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2016 SET-2)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>A station stops to sense the channel once it starts transmitting a frame.</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>The purpose of the jamming signal is to pad the frames that are smaller than the minimum framesize.</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>A station continues to transmit the packet even after the collision is detected.</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>The exponential backoff mechanism reduces the probability of collisionon\nretransmissions.</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>The exponential backoff mechanism reduces the probability of collisionon\nretransmissions.</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/39543/gate2016-2-24#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 15,
          "question": "<p>A sender uses the Stop-and Wait ARQ protocol for reliable transmission of frames. Frames are of size 1000bytes and the transmission rate at the sender is 80Kbps(1Kbps=1000 bits/second). Size of anacknowledgement is 100bytes and the transmission rate at the receiver is 8Kbps. The one-way propagation delay is 100milliseconds. <br>Assuming no frame is lost, the sender throughput is _____bytes/second. <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2016 SET-1)</strong></p>",
          "type": "numeric",
          "options": [],
          "correct_answer": "2500",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/39696/gate2016-1-55#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        }
      ]
    }
  ]
}